先想，再做。当你学会了技巧，却忘了在
Think, then act. When you have learned the techniques, but forget to apply them in
说话中应用，就是在思考之前先行动。为了训练自己先思考，
speech, you are acting before thinking. In order to train yourself to think first,
研究人员采用的策略，就是在冰箱把手上贴一张
devise a strategy that works for you. For the researcher, it was putting a sheet of
对你来说，可能是在开口前先深吸一口气，
newspaper over the fridge handle. For you, it might be taking a deep breath before
说话前数到三、拉一下橡皮筋，甚至用老派方法
speaking, counting to three, pulling on a rubber band, or even the old school
备用办法，也就是在手指上系根线。重点是，当你正在内化
standby, a string around your finger. The point is, while you are internalizing
这些新的声音和节奏时，要创造一个临时提醒，让你把注意力放在
these new sounds and rhythms, to create a stopgap measure to get you to focus on the
关注过程，而不是过多关注目标。学习有四个阶段。我们来看看
process and not so much the goal. The four stages of learning. Let's look at the
你将要经历的转变。一，无意识的无能。
transition you're going to be going through. One, unconscious incompetence.
你甚至不知道自己在犯错。第二阶段，有意识的无能。
You don't even know you're making mistakes. Two, conscious incompetence.
你知道，但你不知道如何修复它们。三，有意识能力。
You're aware, but you don't know how to fix them. Three, conscious competence.
当你非常专注时，其实表现得相当不错。第四阶段，无意识能力。
When you focus really hard, you're actually pretty good. Four, unconscious
能力：你已经把概念内化，它成了第二天性。你
competence. You've internalized the concepts and it's second nature. You're
最有可能正处在从第二阶段迈向第三阶段的边缘。
most likely edging from two to three. To get to four, the key is consistent
要达到第四阶段，关键是持续练习，每天至少 15 分钟，
practice, a minimum of 15 minutes per day, plus applying the techniques whenever you
并且每次说话时都应用这些技巧。
talk.